Drew Cook

Software Engineer • (225) 328-1000 drewcook29@gmail.com • drewcook.dev • github.com/drewcook • linkedin.com/in/drewcook2

SUMMARY

I am a seasoned, full stack software engineer with a specialization utilizing a variety of JavaScript libraries and the .NET framework. I have experience working on projects ranging from government and enterprise web applications, to native web and mobile applications, to websites and tooling for small businesses. I believe that you can build anything you can imagine, turning a thought into a possibility, and allowing the creative mind to run freely without constraints, promotes an environment where one can do some of their best work. The same applies to software, as it's just another medium to work with and mold to fit in with you and your team's ideas. I love working with other creative minds and coming together collaboratively that make for a continually fulfilling, shared experience when those ideas come to fruition.

SKILLS

Fresh Technologies:

- Node.js, Next.js, TypeScript, React, React Native, GraphQL (Apollo), Vue, Nuxt.js
- Cypress, Jest, React Testing Library
- C#,/NET
- Redux, Formik, Material UI, Emotion, CSS modules

Other Technologies:

Enzyme, npm, Webpack, Gulp, HTML, CSS, Sass, Less, Bootstrap, jQuery, PHP, Shopify, WordPress, SharePoint

Databases:

- Relational databases: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL
- Document databases: MongoDB, Google's Cloud Firestore & Firebase

Certifications: Certified ScrumMaster® from ScrumAlliance®; Certificant ID #355624

EXPERIENCE

Gloo - Boulder, CO

Senior Software Engineer, June 2019 – Sept 2020

- Worked in a front-end capacity on the suite of apps across the Gloo platform.
- Leveraged the newest versions of Next.js, React, and Apollo (GraphQL) to render both client-side and server-side Javascript at an advanced level for the apps
- Used Emotion to handle CSS-in-JS for styles to be loaded within the JS bundle
- Used some other JS libraries such as Formik for handling some common form validation things and Material UI as a component library for some great out of the box functionality and design
- Wrote extensive end to end testing with Cypress to ensure production code was stable and flag breaking changes for when new features are added
- Ensured React components and utility functions were stable through unit tests, leveraging Jest and React Testing Library exclusively
- Worked in an agile SDLC with Product Owners, Technical Product Managers, Platform/Backend engineers, other front-end engineers, QA engineers, and other key stakeholders
- Participated in code reviews in Github, managed CI/CD with CircleCI, used Heroku to host PR builds for QA.
- Ensured environment variables were updated within all Kubernetes pods (dev/staging/production) held in Docker containers to keep things synced throughout iterations

Drew Cook

Software Engineer • (225) 328-1000 drewcook29@gmail.com • drewcook.dev • github.com/drewcook • linkedin.com/in/drewcook2

- Helped maintain front end javascript NPM packages that housed common code used amongst the front end repositories, version bumps, etc.
- Provided ample documentation about parts of apps, best practices, onboarding docs, flow charts, etc for other engineers that may be getting up to speed on the particular code
- As a senior engineer, I helped onboard many contractors and new employees and mentored when needed to help explain any technologies or concepts that may have been new or challenging

Architect of the Capitol – Washington, DC (remote)

Software Engineer, Mar 2018 – June 2019, Sept 2020 - Present

- Two different periods contracting for the AOC. The most recent period was focused on converting the same project that we built in 2018/2019 from .NET 4.x to .NET Core 3.x. I also spearheaded rewriting the front end from ES6 class-based React components to functional components with hooks. This was a large undertaking. I spent the remainder of the time adding in over 80 test files for all the JavaScript and documenting the process and architecture for future developers. I also spent my time mentoring other developers on the team who were new to React and front end development with JavaScript frameworks.
- IT Contractor role through Evolver, Inc. Working as a full stack engineer for internal projects for the Architect of the Capitol division
- Helped build out the layouts, functionality, and responsiveness for a SharePoint intranet that is used by the
 entire organization and its employees as well as provide support and development on other internal applications
 used by classified, power-holding users in the Capitol Building
- Converted over legacy code to using modern frameworks and architecture patterns that can be modularized and well tested. Leveraging React, Jest, Enzyme, .NET Web API, and Webpack
- Using vanilla JS (ES6), Typescript with React, Redux, and jQuery to create reusable UI components and Client-side Web Parts within a SharePoint environment, with SCSS for styles and Webpack to handle the build process
- Integrate with SharePoint REST APIs to work with stored data in the environment, using CAML queries, Promises, etc.
- Helped mentor other team members on pieces of code / development concepts when the time was needed
- Used Team Foundation Server for task management and Scrum principles

Evolver, Inc. – Denver, CO

Software Engineer, Apr 2017 – June 2019

- Working as a front end engineer for an enterprise level web application, creating and maintaining new and existing features and functionality.
- Using React and Redux to create reusable UI components throughout the application.
- Eliminating duplicate code by converting old static Javascript into React to keep things DRY.
- Implemented a front end testing harness consisting of Jest and Enzyme to ensure quality code is written
- Integrating the front end code with the middle tier and backend written in C# and the .NET environment.
- Writing C# code to ensure data is being passed effectively from back end up to the front end and vice versa
- Used Jira for task management and Scrum principles

Althea Web Services – Denver, CO

Owner, June 2014 – Present

- Sole-proprietor of a small business that provides web development services for a range of clients including digital marketing agencies, single-owned small businesses, and freelancers.
- Assets provided include website designs, mobile-responsive websites, custom WordPress plugin development, custom WordPress themes, Shopify ecommerce stores, web hosting, domain and server maintenance, logo design, and SEO.
- Assets are created for the client, where the custom functionality on the back end admin areas are tuned uniquely for the client's needs.

Drew Cook

Software Engineer • (225) 328-1000 drewcook29@gmail.com • drewcook.dev • github.com/drewcook • linkedin.com/in/drewcook2

Crawford & O'Brien – Tempe, AZ (remote) Lead Web Developer, Sep 2015 – Apr 2017

- Served as the lead developer for a digital marketing agency performing any and all tech related tasks for the agency including but not limited to: full Wordpress builds, custom themes, support on existing builds and performing client updates, domain transfers and content migration, email maintenance, server maintenance, security and hacker prevention, automated backups of websites and databases, site speed optimization, social media integration, Google site verification with Webmaster Tools and Search Console, basic on-page SEO, and Google Analytics.
- In charge of managing and maintaining the websites, domains, and hosting for around 40 different clients, often working directly with the clients to find out their needs and accomplishing the tasks needed to meet those.

 Being the main point of contact for direct requests for their websites and interacting one-on-one with them.
- Acted as lead on e-commerce sites through Shopify's framework, working with premium themes as well as building custom themes from scratch, integrating with Amazon fulfillment centers, building out newsletter campaigns and integrating through popups and forms, implementing HTML5 video, and tying in with authorized credit card processing companies to take payments as well as with Paypal.
- Directed and managed other developers throughout my tenure, delegating work loads, different sectors of our client base, and assigning out tasks to the appropriate developer as they would come in. Composed processes for different situations pertaining to our development department for other developers to follow through step-by-step. Documentation of all of our logins and credentials for every factor of our department.

Access-Now - Centennial, CO

Web Designer, Dec 2014 – Jan 2015

- Worked on a small team of developers within an agency to design and build dynamic, responsive websites for small and large businesses exclusively through WordPress.
- Worked with a variety of premium WordPress themes, and created child themes for custom styling and functionality.
- Created custom logo designs as well as menus and brochures through Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Maintained SQL databases and domains through Plesk and cPanel admins.

EDUCATION

SeedPaths - Denver, CO

Aug 2014 - Oct 2014

- 8-week intensive software and professional development boot camp designed to become a full stack .NET developer.
- Software development: Fundamentals of object-oriented programming: C#, .NET MVC 4, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Microsoft SQL Server, using relational databases and working primarily through Visual Studio 2012
- Professional development: high energy, confidence, professionalism, intellectual curiosity, & self-management

Louisiana State University – Baton Rouge, LA

Aug 2008 - May 2011

- Landscape Architecture & Communication Studies
- Related Coursework: Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, AutoCAD